LookAt can be used to make a gameobject's
LookAt 関数を使用すれば、あるゲームオブジェクトの前方方向が
forward direction point at another
つねに空間上にある別の位置（Transform）に向くように
transform in the world. In this example
させることが出来ます。このサンプルでは
our samoflange prop is falling and
prop_samoflange オブジェクトが落下していて、 hoverpad から
bouncing off of our hoverpad.
跳ね落ちそうになっています。
Our camera is pointing at the hoverpad,
ゲームビューで確認できるように、カメラは
as you can see in the game view.
hoverpad の方向に向いています。
But what if we want to make it look at the
しかし、もし落下しているオブジェクトに
falling object? We can use the LookAt
向けたい場合どうするかが問題です。この場合は LookAt を
function inside of update in order to
update 関数の代わりに使用すれば
achieve this. In this script you can see
大丈夫です。このスクリプトでは
that we make a reference to the object
探そうとしているオブジェクトに対する参照を
that we wish to look for.
作成することが出来ます。
A variable called 'target' of type transform.
ここでは Transform 型の変数で targetという名前にします。
We then use the transform.LookAt function
ここで transform.LookAt 関数を使用すれば
to tell our object to look at the target.
オブジェクトがターゲットの方向に向けることが出来ます。
Now we'll simply apply this to our camera
それではこのスクリプトをカメラに適用したうえで
and drag on the prop samoflange object
prop_samoflange オブジェクトを追跡対象のオブジェクトとすることにして
as the object to track.
ドラッグ＆ドロップします。
Now when I press play
これでゲーム再生をすれば
our camera is constantly facing the object.
カメラはつねにオブジェクトの方向を向きます。
Remember that you can toggle between global
画面上部のツールバーでグローバル座標軸と
and local axis representation at the top
ローカル座標軸の間を切り替えられることを
of the interface.
覚えておくべきです。
This is with global, and if I toggle to local
グローバル座標の場合は次のとおりで、ローカル座標に
you can see my forward direction is
切り替えるとオブジェクトの前方方向がオブジェクトになるように
facing the object.
変化します。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)